Guide to the Mark Estren Papers, 1961 - 1968
Mark Estren Papers 1961 - 1968
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Estren, Mark James.
2012-18
0.4
2
Mark Estren, Wesleyan class of 1968, served several positions at the WESU radio station of Wesleyan University during the 1960s, including as General Director from 1965 to 1967.
The Mark Estren Papers collection contains Estren's papers from WESU, covering a date range of 1961 to 1968. The bulk of the collection consists of program guides which were printed every two weeks (excepting school breaks). There are also various news items and press releases, including chronicles of several on-air marathons by WESU deejay Jeffrey Taylor.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Donation by Mark Estren, 2012.
Biographical Note
What would come to be called WESU began in 1939 when two students living in Clark Hall connected a transmitter to a phonograph and began broadcasting 78 rpm records. To provide a signal to other buildings, they extended ran their antenna wire though the utility tunnels which connected the buildings. The station quickly became a campus fixture, broadcasting throughout the Middletown area in the early 1940's on an AM signal with the under the call letters WES. In 1950, updated Federal Communications Commission law granted the station its four-letter WESU. In 1965, sophomore Mark Estren became general manager. During his three-year tenure, WESU enjoyed phenomenal success, with the staff increasing from 8 to over 150. The station received several national spotlights, including several on-air endurance marathons by DJ Jeffrey Taylor, and was showcased as the December 1967 "Station of the Month" in the magazine College Radio.
The Mark Estren Papers collection consists of Estren's collection of WESU program guides from 1961 to 1968 and a collection of news items and press releases from his time as general manager. Estren also served as music director, program director, and a member of the WESU board of directors. He graduated in 1968.
Collection Overview
The Mark Estren Papers includes materials from 1961 to 1968 and includes program guides which were printed every two weeks (excepting school breaks) and news clippings, and press releases.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Estren, Mark James.; College radio stations --United States.; Radio stations --United States --History.; WESU (Radio station: Middletown, Conn.)
Related Material
WESU Records, 1943-[ongoing], Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - WESU program guides, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - WESU program guides, 1962 (Folder 2)
  - WESU program guides, 1963 (Folder 3)
  - WESU program guides, 1964 (Folder 4)
  - WESU program guides, 1965 (Folder 5)
  - WESU program guides, 1966 (Folder 6)
  - WESU program guides, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - WESU program guides, 1968 (Folder 8)
  - Jeffrey Taylor on-air marathons (Folder 9)
  - Press releases (Folder 10)
  - WESU news articles (Folder 11)
  - College Radio magazines (Folder 12)
  - IBS and WMHC program guides (Folder 13)
  - Oversize newspapers with articles about WESU (Box 2, Folder 1)